# AMIT SAMANT

iOS Developer

### INFO

#### **ADDRESS**

59, ramganj, jinsi, Indore, 452006, India

#### PHONE

+91 93409 32806

#### **EMAIL**

amitsamant@outlook.com

### LINKS

Twitter.com/amitsamant\_dev

Linkedin.com/in/amitsamant-dev/

Github.com/DominatorVbN

amitdev.codes

Stack Overflow

Hackerrank.com/amitsamant\_dev

# **SKILLS**

iOS Development

Swift

SwiftUI

SDK (Cocoapods)

iPadOS

ARKit

CoreML

### **PROFILE**

Computer science undergraduate and an iOS Developer with 1.5 years of experience. I have done internships in multiple startups, as a intern i have gained a lots of knowledge of development with the help of my seniors and mentors, as i am exploring the world of iOS Development it's getting more and more fascinating i want to gain more knowledge by working on products that are used by a large user base. I am looking to gain experience at a major app company with millions of users.

### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

### iOS Developer Trainee, Engineerbabu

Indore

Jul 2019 — Present

Developing Event 365 an event management application with it's counter app that enable user to get information about near by events to them. Event 365 project has two separate applications proceeding there way to launch.

Event 365 (Event searching platform)

- Intuitive animation using different animation Apis like Property Animators, View Animators, Core Animation.
- · Custom view element with smooth gestures.
- · Robust Network stack developed on top of Moya stack.

### Event 365 host (Event management)

- · Roles and permission managed dynamic UI.
- · QR Code recognition for checking in attendees of events.
- · Admin and super admin levels of role management.

### iOS Developer Intern, MMF Infotech

Indore

Jan 2019 — May 2019

CFSS is an app with uniques feature to provide after sales services to its users.

CFSS (products porfolio and customer care services)

- · built entire app from scratch to deployment,
- Implemented custom UI element to fit design needs of the application,

Version Control Systems

Continuous Integration

Java

C/C++

# **HOBBIES**

Gaming

Travelling

Twitter

**Animes** 

**Fitness** 

## **LANGUAGES**

Hindi

English

Bengali

Integrated Zendesk sdk.

Helpmaster (Voice accesbile forms)

- · This app was specifically designed for motor disabled persons,
- · This app allows user to fill form via there voice,
- voice recognition by Siri's voice to text engine and feature extraction using Dialogflow api.

### iOS Developer Intern, Natraj Infotech

Indore

Aug 2018 — Dec 2018

Built feedback gathering enterprise application "**Kashish**" from scratch to launch. Optimized the app to work on all iOS devices by extensively using **Autolayout** and size classes, app was optimized to adaptively change it's layout according to diffrent screen sizes.

# **COURSES**

### iOS Development Bootcamp, CodeBetter

Jun 2018 — Aug 2018

### Java, Online School of Programming

May 2016 — Sep 2016

### C/C++, Online School of Programming

Jan 2016 — May 2019

# **EDUCATION**

### Computer Science Engineering, Rajiv Gandhi Technical University, Bhopal

Indore

Jul 2016 — Mar 2020

7.03 CGPA upto 7th Semester.

# **EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

Speaker - ARKit, Swift india Confrence

Indore

Jul 2019 — Jul 2019

Co - Organiser, Swift India Conference

Indore

Jul 2019 — Jul 2019